Guide to the Danbury Remembers – Conversations With a Community: Danbury History Project Oral Histories. OH 001
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Danbury Remembers, Conversations With a Community: Danbury History Project Oral Histories.
2002-2004
OH 001
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
3.0 Linear feet 2 boxes, 12 audiotapes
Oral histories from the Danbury Remembers project. The goal of the project was to record a series of oral history interviews with various present and past residents of Danbury.
Danbury History Project
Provenance
Histories collected by the Archives between 2002-2004
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Danbury Remembers – Conversations With a Community was part of the Danbury History Project designed to aid with curriculum revision in the Danbury public schools, centralize historical resources, and develop an oral history program that described Danbury's evolution into the city it is today.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains interviews with persons raging in age roughly from 50 to 90. There are 11 interviews conducted with 10 interviewees recorded on cassette. Interviewers volunteered for the project and were given training by Meg Moughan at the WCSU Archives. Description of the oral histories was contructed by the interviewer with guidelines provided by the Archives. Interviewees were chosen at random. Interviews contain reflections on life of working people from the 1930s to the present. Transcripts, where they exist, are linked to from the inventory.
Arrangement
Item are arranged alphabetically.
The tapes are grouped into 1 series:
Inventory
Balmforth High School (Danbury, Conn.); Boyce, Milton.; Buzzaid, Theresa -- Interviewer.; Danbury High School (Danbury, Conn.); Don, Cal.; Enke, Anna.; Friedman, Sylvia.; Fusco, Sharon.; Hermann, Beatrice -- Interviewer.; Hollander, Janet -- Interviewer.; Johnson, Dorothy.; Leahy, John W.; London, Nancy -- Interviewer.; Moody, Marilyn.; Moody, Ted.; Parkhurst, Doug.; Ruderman, Lilyan.; Audiotapes.; Danbury (Conn.); Danbury (Conn.) -- Flood, 1955.; Danbury (Conn.) -- History.; English language Study and teaching Foreign speakers; Oral histories (discipline).; Oral histories (document genres).; Railroads Employees.; Transcripts.
- Inventory
  - Boyce, Milton (interview), Oct 21, 2003 (Box 1, Tape 1)
    General note
    View transcript
    Scope and Contents note
    Number of tapes: 1 (90 minute)
    Total minutes of recording: 90 min
    Quality of recording: Overall, good, but interview ends abruptly and the microphone falls 3 times causing distraction.
    Interviewer: Nancy London
    Location: Milton Boyce's home?
    Interview topic (overall subject): Milton Boyce's life in Danbury, emphasis on his work and civil service; Childhood; Family history; employment & education; Danbury social life; Marriage; World War II years; Civic organizations; Danbury changes; History and politics of Danbury.
    Years span covered by interview: 1910-2003
    Interview #: 1
  - Dow, Cal (interview), Oct 21, 2003 (Box 1, Tape 2)
    No transcript available.
    Total minutes of recording: ~60 min
    Quality of recording: Good
    Interviewer: Hollander, Janet
    Location: Danbury Senior Center
    Interview topic (overall subject): Don's life in Danbury, Marion Anderson, Russian Orthodox Church, Dr. Weil, Still River mercury poisoning, Land Trust, Tarrywile Park, Danbury Fair, Charles Ives, James Pegolotti, Howard Turelle.
    Years span covered by interview: 1950s-present
  - Enke, Anna (interview), Sep 1, 2004 (Box 1, Tape 3)
    Interview topic (overall subject): Enke's life in Danbury; Lake Candlewood.
    Years span covered by interview: 1967-present
  - Friedman, Sylvia (interview), Sep 7, 2004 (Box 1, Tape 4)
    Quality of recording: Poor, substantial background noise
    Location: "The Garden?"
    Interview topic (overall subject): Friedman's life in Danbury; Childhood; Working in a bakery
    Years span covered by interview: 1917-present
  - Fusco, Sharon (interview), Jan 8, 2004 (Box 1, Tape 5)
    Number of tapes: 1 of 2 90 minute
    Quality of recording: Tape 1 side A: very good side B; very good, stopped before tape ran out.
    Interviewer: Beatrice Hermann
    Location: WCSU Archives
    Interview topic (overall subject): Sharon's life and her work in developing an ESL program in the Danbury Public Schools; Early years; College at WestConn; Danbury, first impressions of city; Church; Teaching Certification; Laboratory Schools; First Years of Teaching; Teaching in Ridgefield; ESL in Danbury, the start; ESL transitions in district; Danbury immigration trends; ESL today
    Years span covered by interview: 1945-2004
  - Fusco, Sharon (interview), Feb 4, 2004 (Box 1, Tape 6)
    Number of tapes: 2 of 2 90 minute
    Total minutes of recording: 25 min
    Quality of recording: very good.
    Interview topic (overall subject): Sharon's life and her work in developing an ESL program in the Danbury Public Schools; Educational institutions and associations
    Interview #: 2
  - Johnson, Dorothy (interview), Oct 22, 2003 (Box 1, Tape 7)
    Number of tapes: 1 90 minute
    Total minutes of recording: 35 min
    Quality of recording: no background noise, good overall
    Interviewer: ?
    Location: WCSU Archives?
    Interview topic (overall subject): Life in Danbury
    Years span covered by interview: 1921 - present
  - Moody, Ted and Marilyn Moody (interview), Oct 9, 2003 (Box 1, Tape 8)
    No transcript available
    Total minutes of recording: 50 minutes
    Quality of recording: Side A: no background noise, good overall; Side B: same
    Years span covered by interview: 1920 - present
  - Parkhurst, Doug (interview), Oct 9, 2003 (Box 1, Tape 9)
    Number of tapes: 1 90min
    Interview topic (overall subject): Life in Danbury, Business transition in Danbury
    Years span covered by interview: 1950-present
  - Ruderman, Lilyan (interview), Nov 11, 2003 (Box 1, Tape 10)
    Quality of recording: Fair
    Interviewer: Morris, Anne
    Location: Dr. Ruderman's home, 5 Washington Ave.
    Interview topic (overall subject): Dr Ruderman's life in Danbury; Early years in New York; Working at Hunter College; Meeting Albert Einstein; Special Education; Danbury Hospital; Victor Ruderman; Singing; Metropolitan School of Music.
    Years span covered by interview: 1930s-present
  - Stetson, Jack (interview), Oct 8, 2003 (Box 1, Tape 11)
    Number of tapes: 1 of 2 90min
    Interviewer: Theresa Buzaid
    Interview topic (overall subject): Danbury Fair
    Years span covered by interview: 1940-1975
  - Stetson, Jack (interview), Oct 8, 2003 (Box 1, Tape 12)
    Number of tapes: 2 of 2 90min
    Total minutes of recording: ~30min
    Quality of recording:
  - Documentation Files, 2003-2004 (Box 2)
    Contains training materials, correspondence with interviewers, and planning documents.